# 桃仁排队了啊 一道大菜
That's walnut kernels lining up! A 'big' dish
# 鸭子的肛门处（清理干净）
Clean up the anal area of the duck
# 这边呢 鸭骚
Here, (remove) the preen gland
# 可骚了这个 可有味了
This smells really bad. It will produce a terrible flavor
# 我看有舌头没有 没有
Let me check if the tongue is still there
# 这很关键啊
This is really important
# 大爷能给您舌头么
Da Ye, it's not possible that they keep the tongue
# 那舌头贵着呢
Tongues are expensive
# 那舌头早卖钱去了
They must have sold it
# 这里有根管 食管
Here's a tube. The gullet
# 得把管给抽出来
We need to pull it out
# 看啊 关键这点的啊
Look. This is important
# 挤出来可都是脏东西
I am squeezing out the dirty stuff
# 这鸭子里边大脏鼻涕
The dirty snot in the duck
# 把这鸭子好好的洗一洗
Wash the duck thoroughly
# 你看这水 倍儿脏
Look. The water is pretty dirty
# 这鸭子在做之前首先得腌
Before cooking, we need to marinate the duck
# 用盐要搓洗
Rub it with salt
# 腿 肚皮里边
Legs. Inside the abdominal cavity
# 拿手（抹匀）让它便于入味
Spread the salt with your hands to let flavor penetrate
# 第二步搁香料
Second, add the spices
# 大料 花椒 小茴香（桂皮）
Star anise, Sichuan peppercorns, fennel seed (and cinnamon)
# 料酒 姜葱来点
Chinese cooking wine, and some ginger and green onion
# 腌的时候我们腌两个小时
Marinate the duck for 2 hours
# 因为鸭子大 得入味
Because this is a big duck. We need to wait for the flavor penetration
# 我们时不时就要给它翻一翻
Flip the duck from time to time
# 今天咱采取煮的办法
Today we will boil the duck
# 因为咱家没有那么大的蒸锅
Because we don't have a steaming pot that's big enough
# 这个先腌一会儿
Let's marinate it for now
# 待会儿咱们给它煮上
We'll boil it later
# 借这个机会咱们备点料
At this time, prepare some other ingredients
# 炒点花椒 晾一晾
Stir-fry some Sichuan peppercorns, then cool them
# 这个桃仁我们要在处理的时候
The walnut kernels... when processing it
# 要拿水泡 开水泡
You need to soak it with boiling water
# 拿牙签把皮给扒下去
Then remove the skin with a toothpick
# 要不然它就涩苦
Otherwise it's gonna taste bitter
# 这油温别太大
Don't use very high oil temperature
# 这一定要用老桃仁 老桃仁香
You must use ripe walnut kernels. They're more aromatic
# 差不多了 尽快的离开油
That's almost done. Pick it out from the oil asap
# 为什么要早炸啊
Why frying it prior to cooking the duck?
# 早炸得让它晾凉了 它脆
We need to cool it down such that it becomes crispy
# 好了 鸭子够时间了
Okay. The duck is done
# 这个水里边有葱姜 黄酒 盐
There're ginger, green onion, Huangjiu cooking wine, and salt
# 盖盖儿
Put the lid on
# 三十五分钟
35 minutes
# 大爷今儿这个菜都费劲的菜
Da Ye is preparing some really complicated dishes today
# 擀面杖来了
Here's the rolling pin
# 你看这花椒 现在非常酥是吧
Look at the Sichuan peppercorns. Very crispy now, right?
# 在过去 因为在酒店上班
In the past, I was working in restaurants
# 这鸭子不能带骨头
The duck must be served without bones
# 那就好好把这鸭子去骨
So I needed to debone the duck carefully
# 去骨这肉少了
However, that'll remove some meat as well
# 肉少了拿虾找补
So we compensate with shrimp
# 弄点馅给它一瓤
Prepare some mashed shrimp as the stuffing
# 吃起来又方便
That's also convenient to eat
# 最好吃的还就是虾
Shrimp is the most delicious food
# 你看这个是小窍门啊
This is a trick
# 找葱芯 为什么啊
Use the core of the green onion
# 你看这葱芯肉厚水分足
The green onion core is thick and full of moisture
# 这是我师父
This is a small trick
# 教给我这么一个小绝招
taught by my master
# 李党为什么说你来着了呢
Li Dang, your trip here is worth it
# 把花椒面和葱混到一起
Mix the Sichuan peppercorn powder with the minced green onion
# 加上盐 葱椒盐
Then add some salt. That's onion-pepper-salt
# 你看二伯
Hey, Er Bai
# 二伯一看就有丰富的经验
Er Bai is very experienced
# 二伯您回答非常正确啊
Er Bai is absolutely right
# 得到你表扬真不容易
It's difficult to be praised by you
# 我从来不表扬人
I hardly ever praise people
# 您一下就说对了
but you got it right immediately
# 你要让李党说李党都说不出来
Li Dang cannot answer this question
# 说不出来 真说不出来
No, I cannot... Seriously
# 这就是比椒盐好吃啊 香啊
This is definitely better than pepper-salt. It's more aromatic
# 特别香这个
Extremely aromatic
# 这解决什么问题呢
How does it work?
# 比如香酥鸡 香酥鸭
Say, when cooking fried crispy chicken or duck
# 有时候这底味 味道不足
The base flavor is not strong enough sometimes
# 原料底下给抹点葱椒盐
In this case, spread some onion-pepper-salt underneath the meat
# 这就是师父的绝招在这
That's a great trick from your master
# 而且刚才一剁
Also, as we just chopped it
# 花椒的香味跟葱的鲜味
The aromas of peppercorns and green onion...
# 马上就产生出来了
are activated immediately
# 而且那鸭子出来味道就不一样了
The duck will also taste differently after cooking
# 你看这刚才准备的
Look. This is what we just prepared
# 肥膘肉切碎
Minced pork fat
# 虾馅 一斤虾肉要搁
Mashed shrimp stuffing. In 500 grams of shrimp,
# 二两五左右的肥膘肉
We add about 125 g of pork fat
# 葱姜 搁点酒 这叫什么
Green onion, ginger, and some cooking wine. What's this?
# 葱姜酒水
green onion-ginger-wine
# 倒这虾胶里头
Pour it into the shrimp stuffing
# 淀粉 盐
Starch and salt
# 白胡椒粉 去腥的啊
White pepper powder. This removes the fishy odor
# 蛋清也别太多 一半就够了
Don't add too much egg white. Just a half would be enough
# 料都放齐了 抓匀搅拌上劲
That's all the ingredients. Mix until it becomes sticky
# 这虾胶打的还真是腻乎啊
The shrimp stuffing is indeed quite sticky
# 好 有劲儿了
Okay. Now it's sticky enough
# 咱就等鸭子了啊 好嘞
Let's wait for the duck to be done
# 走
Pick it out
# 咱们这鸭子晾凉了
After cooling the duck
# 晾凉了咱们给它把骨头拆了
Let's remove the bones
# 拆骨的时候脯朝下
When deboning, the duck breast should be put towards the chopping board
# 拆出来是整个的
In that case, you'll have a complete duck at last
# 我们这拆骨要拆净它
We need to remove the bones completely
# 好了 行
Ok. It's done
# 撒点淀粉就行 粘上它
Sprinkle some starch. Let it stick to the duck
# 它一炸能托一下
When frying, it's gonna hold the duck together
# 因为这刚做的鸭子
The duck is freshly made
# 一会炸的时候表面好酥脆
Hence the surface is gonna be crispy after frying
# 倒油 烧上了啊
Add some oil. Heating now
# 葱椒盐 铺上了
Green onion-pepper-salt. Spread on the duck
# 铺上了要拍淀粉
After that, pat some starch on the duck
# 这鸭子是新煮的
The duck is freshly boiled
# 淀粉要稍微多一点
Hence we need to use more starch
# 连拍带弹 定型了啊
Pat it to fix the shape
# 这样炸出来它不掉它不散了
Then it's not gonna fall apart when frying
# 这会咱们就开始往上抹馅了
Let's apply the stuffing now
# 我们厨师啊
As a chef
# 不单单是会做菜
Cooking is not our only profession
# 还要会瓦匠
We need to be bricklayers sometimes
# 要会抹 抹平
You should be able to spread it evenly
# 薄厚要均匀 好了
The thickness should be even. That's done
# 还一个关键点
One more important trick
# 让它彻底馅和鸭肉融为一体
is to fuse the stuffing with the duck completely
# 师父这叫什么
What's this trick, master?
# 这叫瓤 瓤馅儿么
This is called 'rang'. 'Rang' the stuffing
# 轻轻的排一下 然后再给抹平了
Cut it gently. Then flatten the surface again
# 这就是师父的绝招啊
That's a secret trick from your master
# 这就是烹饪中的技巧
A trick in cooking
# 桃仁 这样你粘完之后
The walnut kernel. In this way,
# 打死它都不会脱了
The stuffing will never fall from the duck
# 桃仁排队了啊
That's walnut kernels lining up
# 一推齐活 一道大菜
Press it, done! A 'big' dish
# 往那一出溜 油温六成热
Slide it into the wok. The oil temperature is 180 degrees Celsius
# 这油温也不能太高 也不能太凉
It shouldn't be too high, nor too low
# 定型的时候就得高点 先定
When fixing the shape, you need to use a higher oil temperature
# 融为一个整体了吧
That's fusing together
# 鼓起来了 鼓起就熟了
It's swelling up. That's done
# 桃仁酥鸭方 好了
Crispy walnut kernel duck cubes. Done!
# 李党给你尝一个 来
Li Dang, taste it. Come on
# 张嘴 谢谢二伯
Open your mouth. Thank you, Er Bai
# 桃仁这个香 满嘴挂香
The aroma of walnut kernel stays in the whole mouth
# 虾胶这种鲜
The umami taste of the shrimp stuffing
# 鸭子这种特殊的
Also the special taste of duck
# 拿香料腌的这种香味
The aroma from different spices
# 它没有失本味
The original flavor of duck is not gone
# 但是所有的东西
All these ingredients...
# 都是为了突出主味
serve to emphasize the main flavor
# 这个鸭子的香气
The aroma of the duck
# 大爷我跟您说句话
Da Ye, let me tell you
# 从始到终
From the beginning to the end
# 我并没有吃出这葱椒盐的味来
I did not taste the green onion-pepper-salt at all
# 它完全是鸭子的香气
It's completely the aroma of duck
# 就是他做这东西恰到好处
This is perfect cooking
# 要没有葱 坏了
If there's no green onion, it's gonna be terrible
# 要没有葱
Without the green onion
# 它整个的都是花椒味了
It's completely the flavor of peppercorns
# 所以说呢师父 谢谢您
So thank you, master
# 谢谢师父
Thanks, master
# 今天让我学到了
Today I have learnt
# 真正的
The real
# 而且真正马上快失传的（技法）
cooking technique that's gonna be lost
# 我师父今年都65了
My master is 65 years old now
# 很多这样的一个菜品
...and many dishes like this
# 让我非常激动
I am so excited
# 感激师父
I appreciate it a lot for my master
# 感谢你拜了这么一个好的师父
You should thank your master a lot, who is so nice and knowledgeable
# 给师父深深鞠一躬
Bow to your master
# 谢谢师父
Thank you, master!
# 谢谢二伯
Thanks, Er Bai